CHAPTER I.
Down the Rabbit-Hole

Alex was beginning to get very tired of sitting by their sister on the bank, and of having nothing to do: once or twice they had peeped into the book their sister was reading, but it had no pictures or conversations in it, “and what is the use of a book,” thought Alex “without pictures or conversations?”

So they were considering in their own mind (as well as they could, for the hot day made them feel very sleepy and stupid), whether the pleasure of making a daisy-chain would be worth the trouble of getting up and picking the daisies, when suddenly a White Rabbit with pink eyes ran close by them.

There was nothing so very remarkable in that; nor did Alex think it so very much out of the way to hear the Rabbit say to itself, “Oh dear! Oh dear! I shall be late!” (when they thought it over afterwards, it occurred to them that they ought to have wondered at this, but at the time it all seemed quite natural); but when the Rabbit actually took a watch out of its waistcoat-pocket, and looked at it, and then hurried on, Alex started to their feet, for it flashed across their mind that they had never before seen a rabbit with either a waistcoat-pocket, or a watch to take out of it, and burning with curiosity, they ran across the field after it, and fortunately was just in time to see it pop down a large rabbit-hole under the hedge.

In another moment down went Alex after it, never once considering how in the world they were to get out again.

The rabbit-hole went straight on like a tunnel for some way, and then dipped suddenly down, so suddenly that Alex had not a moment to think about stopping themselves before they found themselves falling down a very deep well.

Either the well was very deep, or they fell very slowly, for they had plenty of time as they went down to look about them and to wonder what was going to happen next. First, they tried to look down and make out what they were coming to, but it was too dark to see anything; then they looked at the sides of the well, and noticed that they were filled with cupboards and book-shelves; here and there they saw maps and pictures hung upon pegs. They took down a jar from one of the shelves as they passed; it was labelled “ORANGE MARMALADE”, but to their great disappointment it was empty: they did not like to drop the jar for fear of killing somebody underneath, so managed to put it into one of the cupboards as they fell past it.

“Well!” thought Alex to themselves, “after such a fall as this, I shall think nothing of tumbling down stairs! How brave they’ll all think me at home! Why, I wouldn’t say anything about it, even if I fell off the top of the house!” (Which was very likely true.)

Down, down, down. Would the fall never come to an end? “I wonder how many miles I’ve fallen by this time?” they said aloud. “I must be getting somewhere near the centre of the earth. Let me see: that would be four thousand miles down, I think—” (for, you see, Alex had learnt several things of this sort in their lessons in the schoolroom, and though this was not a very good opportunity for showing off their knowledge, as there was no one to listen to them, still it was good practice to say it over) “—yes, that’s about the right distance—but then I wonder what Latitude or Longitude I’ve got to?” (Alex had no idea what Latitude was, or Longitude either, but thought they were nice grand words to say.)

Presently they began again. “I wonder if I shall fall right through the earth! How funny it’ll seem to come out among the people that walk with their heads downward! The Antipathies, I think—” (they were rather glad there was no one listening, this time, as it didn’t sound at all the right word) “—but I shall have to ask them what the name of the country is, you know. Please, Ma’am, is this New Zealand or Australia?” (and they tried to curtsey as they spoke—fancy curtseying as you’re falling through the air! Do you think you could manage it?) “And what an ignorant little person they’ll think me for asking! No, it’ll never do to ask: perhaps I shall see it written up somewhere.”

Down, down, down. There was nothing else to do, so Alex soon began talking again. “Dinah’ll miss me very much to-night, I should think!” (Dinah was the cat.) “I hope they’ll remember her saucer of milk at tea-time. Dinah my dear! I wish you were down here with me! There are no mice in the air, I’m afraid, but you might catch a bat, and that’s very like a mouse, you know. But do cats eat bats, I wonder?” And here Alex began to get rather sleepy, and went on saying to themselves, in a dreamy sort of way, “Do cats eat bats? Do cats eat bats?” and sometimes, “Do bats eat cats?” for, you see, as they couldn’t answer either question, it didn’t much matter which way they put it. They felt that they were dozing off, and had just begun to dream that they were walking hand in hand with Dinah, and saying to her very earnestly, “Now, Dinah, tell me the truth: did you ever eat a bat?” when suddenly, thump! thump! down they came upon a heap of sticks and dry leaves, and the fall was over.

Alex was not a bit hurt, and they jumped up on to their feet in a moment: they looked up, but it was all dark overhead; before them was another long passage, and the White Rabbit was still in sight, hurrying down it. There was not a moment to be lost: away went Alex like the wind, and was just in time to hear it say, as it turned a corner, “Oh my ears and whiskers, how late it’s getting!” They were close behind it when they turned the corner, but the Rabbit was no longer to be seen: they found themselves in a long, low hall, which was lit up by a row of lamps hanging from the roof.

There were doors all round the hall, but they were all locked; and when Alex had been all the way down one side and up the other, trying every door, they walked sadly down the middle, wondering how they were ever to get out again.

Suddenly they came upon a little three-legged table, all made of solid glass; there was nothing on it except a tiny golden key, and Alex’s first thought was that it might belong to one of the doors of the hall; but, alas! either the locks were too large, or the key was too small, but at any rate it would not open any of them. However, on the second time round, they came upon a low curtain they had not noticed before, and behind it was a little door about fifteen inches high: they tried the little golden key in the lock, and to their great delight it fitted!

Alex opened the door and found that it led into a small passage, not much larger than a rat-hole: they knelt down and looked along the passage into the loveliest garden you ever saw. How they longed to get out of that dark hall, and wander about among those beds of bright flowers and those cool fountains, but they could not even get their head through the doorway; “and even if my head would go through,” thought poor Alex, “it would be of very little use without my shoulders. Oh, how I wish I could shut up like a telescope! I think I could, if I only knew how to begin.” For, you see, so many out-of-the-way things had happened lately, that Alex had begun to think that very few things indeed were really impossible.

There seemed to be no use in waiting by the little door, so they went back to the table, half hoping they might find another key on it, or at any rate a book of rules for shutting people up like telescopes: this time they found a little bottle on it, (“which certainly was not here before,” said Alex,) and round the neck of the bottle was a paper label, with the words “DRINK ME,” beautifully printed on it in large letters.

It was all very well to say “Drink me,” but the wise little Alex was not going to do that in a hurry. “No, I’ll look first,” they said, “and see whether it’s marked ‘poison’ or not”; for they had read several nice little histories about children who had got burnt, and eaten up by wild beasts and other unpleasant things, all because they would not remember the simple rules their friends had taught them: such as, that a red-hot poker will burn you if you hold it too long; and that if you cut your finger very deeply with a knife, it usually bleeds; and they had never forgotten that, if you drink much from a bottle marked “poison,” it is almost certain to disagree with you, sooner or later.

However, this bottle was not marked “poison,” so Alex ventured to taste it, and finding it very nice, (it had, in fact, a sort of mixed flavour of cherry-tart, custard, pine-apple, roast turkey, toffee, and hot buttered toast,) they very soon finished it off.

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

    *      *      *      *      *      *

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

“What a curious feeling!” said Alex; “I must be shutting up like a telescope.”

And so it was indeed: they were now only ten inches high, and their face brightened up at the thought that they were now the right size for going through the little door into that lovely garden. First, however, they waited for a few minutes to see if they were going to shrink any further: they felt a little nervous about this; “for it might end, you know,” said Alex to themselves, “in my going out altogether, like a candle. I wonder what I should be like then?” And they tried to fancy what the flame of a candle is like after the candle is blown out, for they could not remember ever having seen such a thing.

After a while, finding that nothing more happened, they decided on going into the garden at once; but, alas for poor Alex! when they got to the door, they found they had forgotten the little golden key, and when they went back to the table for it, they found they could not possibly reach it: they could see it quite plainly through the glass, and they tried their best to climb up one of the legs of the table, but it was too slippery; and when they had tired themselves out with trying, the poor little thing sat down and cried.

“Come, there’s no use in crying like that!” said Alex to themselves, rather sharply; “I advise you to leave off this minute!” They generally gave themselves very good advice, (though they very seldom followed it), and sometimes they scolded themselves so severely as to bring tears into their eyes; and once they remembered trying to box their own ears for having cheated themselves in a game of croquet they were playing against themselves, for this curious child was very fond of pretending to be two people. “But it’s no use now,” thought poor Alex, “to pretend to be two people! Why, there’s hardly enough of me left to make one respectable person!”

Soon their eye fell on a little glass box that was lying under the table: they opened it, and found in it a very small cake, on which the words “EAT ME” were beautifully marked in currants. “Well, I’ll eat it,” said Alex, “and if it makes me grow larger, I can reach the key; and if it makes me grow smaller, I can creep under the door; so either way I’ll get into the garden, and I don’t care which happens!”

They ate a little bit, and said anxiously to themselves, “Which way? Which way?”, holding their hand on the top of their head to feel which way it was growing, and they were quite surprised to find that they remained the same size: to be sure, this generally happens when one eats cake, but Alex had got so much into the way of expecting nothing but out-of-the-way things to happen, that it seemed quite dull and stupid for life to go on in the common way.

So they set to work, and very soon finished off the cake.

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

    *      *      *      *      *      *

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

CHAPTER II.
The Pool of Tears

“Curiouser and curiouser!” cried Alex (they were so much surprised, that for the moment they quite forgot how to speak good English); “now I’m opening out like the largest telescope that ever was! Good-bye, feet!” (for when they looked down at their feet, they seemed to be almost out of sight, they were getting so far off). “Oh, my poor little feet, I wonder who will put on your shoes and stockings for you now, dears? I’m sure I shan’t be able! I shall be a great deal too far off to trouble myself about you: you must manage the best way you can;—but I must be kind to them,” thought Alex, “or perhaps they won’t walk the way I want to go! Let me see: I’ll give them a new pair of boots every Christmas.”

And they went on planning to themselves how they would manage it. “They must go by the carrier,” they thought; “and how funny it’ll seem, sending presents to one’s own feet! And how odd the directions will look!

     Alex’s Right Foot, Esq.,
       Hearthrug,
         near the Fender,
           (with Alex’s love).

Oh dear, what nonsense I’m talking!”

Just then their head struck against the roof of the hall: in fact they were now more than nine feet high, and they at once took up the little golden key and hurried off to the garden door.

Poor Alex! It was as much as they could do, lying down on one side, to look through into the garden with one eye; but to get through was more hopeless than ever: they sat down and began to cry again.

“You ought to be ashamed of yourself,” said Alex, “a great person like you,” (they might well say this), “to go on crying in this way! Stop this moment, I tell you!” But they went on all the same, shedding gallons of tears, until there was a large pool all round them, about four inches deep and reaching half down the hall.

After a time they heard a little pattering of feet in the distance, and they hastily dried their eyes to see what was coming. It was the White Rabbit returning, splendidly dressed, with a pair of white kid gloves in one hand and a large fan in the other: he came trotting along in a great hurry, muttering to himself as he came, “Oh! the Duchess, the Duchess! Oh! won’t they be savage if I’ve kept them waiting!” Alex felt so desperate that they were ready to ask help of any one; so, when the Rabbit came near them, they began, in a low, timid voice, “If you please, sir—” The Rabbit started violently, dropped the white kid gloves and the fan, and skurried away into the darkness as hard as he could go.

Alex took up the fan and gloves, and, as the hall was very hot, they kept fanning themselves all the time they went on talking: “Dear, dear! How queer everything is to-day! And yesterday things went on just as usual. I wonder if I’ve been changed in the night? Let me think: was I the same when I got up this morning? I almost think I can remember feeling a little different. But if I’m not the same, the next question is, Who in the world am I? Ah, that’s the great puzzle!” And they began thinking over all the children they knew that were of the same age as herself, to see if they could have been changed for any of them.

“I’m sure I’m not Ada,” they said, “for her hair goes in such long ringlets, and mine doesn’t go in ringlets at all; and I’m sure I can’t be Mabel, for I know all sorts of things, and she, oh! she knows such a very little! Besides, she’s she, and I’m I, and—oh dear, how puzzling it all is! I’ll try if I know all the things I used to know. Let me see: four times five is twelve, and four times six is thirteen, and four times seven is—oh dear! I shall never get to twenty at that rate! However, the Multiplication Table doesn’t signify: let’s try Geography. London is the capital of Paris, and Paris is the capital of Rome, and Rome—no, that’s all wrong, I’m certain! I must have been changed for Mabel! I’ll try and say ‘How doth the little—’” and they crossed their hands on their lap as if they were saying lessons, and began to repeat it, but their voice sounded hoarse and strange, and the words did not come the same as they used to do:—

“How doth the little crocodile
    Improve his shining tail,
And pour the waters of the Nile
    On every golden scale!

“How cheerfully he seems to grin,
    How neatly spread his claws,
And welcome little fishes in
    With gently smiling jaws!”

“I’m sure those are not the right words,” said poor Alex, and their eyes filled with tears again as they went on, “I must be Mabel after all, and I shall have to go and live in that poky little house, and have next to no toys to play with, and oh! ever so many lessons to learn! No, I’ve made up my mind about it; if I’m Mabel, I’ll stay down here! It’ll be no use their putting their heads down and saying ‘Come up again, dear!’ I shall only look up and say ‘Who am I then? Tell me that first, and then, if I like being that person, I’ll come up: if not, I’ll stay down here till I’m somebody else’—but, oh dear!” cried Alex, with a sudden burst of tears, “I do wish they would put their heads down! I am so very tired of being all alone here!”

As they said this they looked down at their hands, and was surprised to see that they had put on one of the Rabbit’s little white kid gloves while they were talking. “How can I have done that?” they thought. “I must be growing small again.” They got up and went to the table to measure themselves by it, and found that, as nearly as they could guess, they were now about two feet high, and was going on shrinking rapidly: they soon found out that the cause of this was the fan they were holding, and they dropped it hastily, just in time to avoid shrinking away altogether.

“That was a narrow escape!” said Alex, a good deal frightened at the sudden change, but very glad to find themselves still in existence; “and now for the garden!” and they ran with all speed back to the little door: but, alas! the little door was shut again, and the little golden key was lying on the glass table as before, “and things are worse than ever,” thought the poor child, “for I never was so small as this before, never! And I declare it’s too bad, that it is!”

As they said these words their foot slipped, and in another moment, splash! they were up to their chin in salt water. Their first idea was that they had somehow fallen into the sea, “and in that case I can go back by railway,” they said to themselves. (Alex had been to the seaside once in their life, and had come to the general conclusion, that wherever you go to on the English coast you find a number of bathing machines in the sea, some children digging in the sand with wooden spades, then a row of lodging houses, and behind them a railway station.) However, they soon made out that they were in the pool of tears which they had wept when they were nine feet high.

“I wish I hadn’t cried so much!” said Alex, as they swam about, trying to find their way out. “I shall be punished for it now, I suppose, by being drowned in my own tears! That will be a queer thing, to be sure! However, everything is queer to-day.”

Just then they heard something splashing about in the pool a little way off, and they swam nearer to make out what it was: at first they thought it must be a walrus or hippopotamus, but then they remembered how small they were now, and they soon made out that it was only a mouse that had slipped in like themselves.

“Would it be of any use, now,” thought Alex, “to speak to this mouse? Everything is so out-of-the-way down here, that I should think very likely it can talk: at any rate, there’s no harm in trying.” So they began: “O Mouse, do you know the way out of this pool? I am very tired of swimming about here, O Mouse!” (Alex thought this must be the right way of speaking to a mouse: they had never done such a thing before, but they remembered having seen in their brother’s Latin Grammar, “A mouse—of a mouse—to a mouse—a mouse—O mouse!”) The Mouse looked at them rather inquisitively, and seemed to them to wink with one of its little eyes, but it said nothing.

“Perhaps it doesn’t understand English,” thought Alex; “I daresay it’s a French mouse, come over with William the Conqueror.” (For, with all their knowledge of history, Alex had no very clear notion how long ago anything had happened.) So they began again: “Où est ma chatte?” which was the first sentence in their French lesson-book. The Mouse gave a sudden leap out of the water, and seemed to quiver all over with fright. “Oh, I beg your pardon!” cried Alex hastily, afraid that they had hurt the poor animal’s feelings. “I quite forgot you didn’t like cats.”

“Not like cats!” cried the Mouse, in a shrill, passionate voice. “Would you like cats if you were me?”

“Well, perhaps not,” said Alex in a soothing tone: “don’t be angry about it. And yet I wish I could show you our cat Dinah: I think you’d take a fancy to cats if you could only see her. She is such a dear quiet thing,” Alex went on, half to theirselves, as they swam lazily about in the pool, “and she sits purring so nicely by the fire, licking her paws and washing her face—and she is such a nice soft thing to nurse—and she’s such a capital one for catching mice—oh, I beg your pardon!” cried Alex again, for this time the Mouse was bristling all over, and they felt certain it must be really offended. “We won’t talk about her any more if you’d rather not.”

“We indeed!” cried the Mouse, who was trembling down to the end of his tail. “As if I would talk on such a subject! Our family always hated cats: nasty, low, vulgar things! Don’t let me hear the name again!”

“I won’t indeed!” said Alex, in a great hurry to change the subject of conversation. “Are you—are you fond—of—of dogs?” The Mouse did not answer, so Alex went on eagerly: “There is such a nice little dog near our house I should like to show you! A little bright-eyed terrier, you know, with oh, such long curly brown hair! And it’ll fetch things when you throw them, and it’ll sit up and beg for its dinner, and all sorts of things—I can’t remember half of them—and it belongs to a farmer, you know, and he says it’s so useful, it’s worth a hundred pounds! He says it kills all the rats and—oh dear!” cried Alex in a sorrowful tone, “I’m afraid I’ve offended it again!” For the Mouse was swimming away from them as hard as it could go, and making quite a commotion in the pool as it went.

So they called softly after it, “Mouse dear! Do come back again, and we won’t talk about cats or dogs either, if you don’t like them!” When the Mouse heard this, it turned round and swam slowly back to them: its face was quite pale (with passion, Alex thought), and it said in a low trembling voice, “Let us get to the shore, and then I’ll tell you my history, and you’ll understand why it is I hate cats and dogs.”

It was high time to go, for the pool was getting quite crowded with the birds and animals that had fallen into it: there were a Duck and a Dodo, a Lory and an Eaglet, and several other curious creatures. Alex led the way, and the whole party swam to the shore.

CHAPTER V.
Advice from a Caterpillar

The Caterpillar and Alex looked at each other for some time in silence: at last the Caterpillar took the hookah out of its mouth, and addressed them in a languid, sleepy voice.

“Who are you?” said the Caterpillar.

This was not an encouraging opening for a conversation. Alex replied, rather shyly, “I—I hardly know, sir, just at present—at least I know who I was when I got up this morning, but I think I must have been changed several times since then.”

“What do you mean by that?” said the Caterpillar sternly. “Explain yourself!”

“I can’t explain myself, I’m afraid, sir,” said Alex, “because I’m not myself, you see.”

“I don’t see,” said the Caterpillar.

“I’m afraid I can’t put it more clearly,” Alex replied very politely, “for I can’t understand it myself to begin with; and being so many different sizes in a day is very confusing.”

“It isn’t,” said the Caterpillar.

“Well, perhaps you haven’t found it so yet,” said Alex; “but when you have to turn into a chrysalis—you will some day, you know—and then after that into a butterfly, I should think you’ll feel it a little queer, won’t you?”

“Not a bit,” said the Caterpillar.

“Well, perhaps your feelings may be different,” said Alex; “all I know is, it would feel very queer to me.”

“You!” said the Caterpillar contemptuously. “Who are you?”

Which brought them back again to the beginning of the conversation. Alex felt a little irritated at the Caterpillar’s making such very short remarks, and they drew themselves up and said, very gravely, “I think, you ought to tell me who you are, first.”

“Why?” said the Caterpillar.

Here was another puzzling question; and as Alex could not think of any good reason, and as the Caterpillar seemed to be in a very unpleasant state of mind, they turned away.

“Come back!” the Caterpillar called after them. “I’ve something important to say!”

This sounded promising, certainly: Alex turned and came back again.

“Keep your temper,” said the Caterpillar.

“Is that all?” said Alex, swallowing down their anger as well as they could.

“No,” said the Caterpillar.

Alex thought they might as well wait, as they had nothing else to do, and perhaps after all it might tell them something worth hearing. For some minutes it puffed away without speaking, but at last it unfolded its arms, took the hookah out of its mouth again, and said, “So you think you’re changed, do you?”

“I’m afraid I am, sir,” said Alex; “I can’t remember things as I used—and I don’t keep the same size for ten minutes together!”

“Can’t remember what things?” said the Caterpillar.

“Well, I’ve tried to say “How doth the little busy bee,” but it all came different!” Alex replied in a very melancholy voice.

“Repeat, “You are old, Father William,’” said the Caterpillar.

Alex folded their hands, and began:—

“You are old, Father William,” the young man said,
    “And your hair has become very white;
And yet you incessantly stand on your head—
    Do you think, at your age, it is right?”

“In my youth,” Father William replied to his son,
    “I feared it might injure the brain;
But, now that I’m perfectly sure I have none,
    Why, I do it again and again.”

“You are old,” said the youth, “as I mentioned before,
    And have grown most uncommonly fat;
Yet you turned a back-somersault in at the door—
    Pray, what is the reason of that?”

“In my youth,” said the sage, as he shook his grey locks,
    “I kept all my limbs very supple
By the use of this ointment—one shilling the box—
    Allow me to sell you a couple?”

“You are old,” said the youth, “and your jaws are too weak
    For anything tougher than suet;
Yet you finished the goose, with the bones and the beak—
    Pray, how did you manage to do it?”

“In my youth,” said his father, “I took to the law,
    And argued each case with my wife;
And the muscular strength, which it gave to my jaw,
    Has lasted the rest of my life.”

“You are old,” said the youth, “one would hardly suppose
    That your eye was as steady as ever;
Yet you balanced an eel on the end of your nose—
    What made you so awfully clever?”

“I have answered three questions, and that is enough,”
    Said his father; “don’t give yourself airs!
Do you think I can listen all day to such stuff?
    Be off, or I’ll kick you down stairs!”

“That is not said right,” said the Caterpillar.

“Not quite right, I’m afraid,” said Alex, timidly; “some of the words have got altered.”

“It is wrong from beginning to end,” said the Caterpillar decidedly, and there was silence for some minutes.

The Caterpillar was the first to speak.

“What size do you want to be?” it asked.

“Oh, I’m not particular as to size,” Alex hastily replied; “only one doesn’t like changing so often, you know.”

“I don’t know,” said the Caterpillar.

Alex said nothing: they had never been so much contradicted in their life before, and they felt that they were losing their temper.

“Are you content now?” said the Caterpillar.

“Well, I should like to be a little larger, sir, if you wouldn’t mind,” said Alex: “three inches is such a wretched height to be.”

“It is a very good height indeed!” said the Caterpillar angrily, rearing itself upright as it spoke (it was exactly three inches high).

“But I’m not used to it!” pleaded poor Alex in a piteous tone. And they thought of themselves, “I wish the creatures wouldn’t be so easily offended!”

“You’ll get used to it in time,” said the Caterpillar; and it put the hookah into its mouth and began smoking again.

This time Alex waited patiently until it chose to speak again. In a minute or two the Caterpillar took the hookah out of its mouth and yawned once or twice, and shook itself. Then it got down off the mushroom, and crawled away in the grass, merely remarking as it went, “One side will make you grow taller, and the other side will make you grow shorter.”

“One side of what? The other side of what?” thought Alex to themselves.

“Of the mushroom,” said the Caterpillar, just as if they had asked it aloud; and in another moment it was out of sight.

Alex remained looking thoughtfully at the mushroom for a minute, trying to make out which were the two sides of it; and as it was perfectly round, they found this a very difficult question. However, at last they stretched their arms round it as far as they would go, and broke off a bit of the edge with each hand.

“And now which is which?” they said to themselves, and nibbled a little of the right-hand bit to try the effect: the next moment they felt a violent blow underneath their chin: it had struck their foot!

They were a good deal frightened by this very sudden change, but they felt that there was no time to be lost, as they were shrinking rapidly; so they set to work at once to eat some of the other bit. Their chin was pressed so closely against their foot, that there was hardly room to open their mouth; but they did it at last, and managed to swallow a morsel of the lefthand bit.

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

    *      *      *      *      *      *

*      *      *      *      *      *      *

“Come, my head’s free at last!” said Alex in a tone of delight, which changed into alarm in another moment, when they found that their shoulders were nowhere to be found: all they could see, when they looked down, was an immense length of neck, which seemed to rise like a stalk out of a sea of green leaves that lay far below them.

“What can all that green stuff be?” said Alex. “And where have my shoulders got to? And oh, my poor hands, how is it I can’t see you?” They were moving them about as they spoke, but no result seemed to follow, except a little shaking among the distant green leaves.

As there seemed to be no chance of getting their hands up to their head, they tried to get their head down to them, and was delighted to find that their neck would bend about easily in any direction, like a serpent. They had just succeeded in curving it down into a graceful zigzag, and was going to dive in among the leaves, which they found to be nothing but the tops of the trees under which they had been wandering, when a sharp hiss made them draw back in a hurry: a large pigeon had flown into their face, and was beating them violently with its wings.

“Serpent!” screamed the Pigeon.

“I’m not a serpent!” said Alex indignantly. “Let me alone!”

“Serpent, I say again!” repeated the Pigeon, but in a more subdued tone, and added with a kind of sob, “I’ve tried every way, and nothing seems to suit them!”

“I haven’t the least idea what you’re talking about,” said Alex.

“I’ve tried the roots of trees, and I’ve tried banks, and I’ve tried hedges,” the Pigeon went on, without attending to them; “but those serpents! There’s no pleasing them!”

Alex was more and more puzzled, but they thought there was no use in saying anything more till the Pigeon had finished.

“As if it wasn’t trouble enough hatching the eggs,” said the Pigeon; “but I must be on the look-out for serpents night and day! Why, I haven’t had a wink of sleep these three weeks!”

“I’m very sorry you’ve been annoyed,” said Alex, who was beginning to see its meaning.

“And just as I’d taken the highest tree in the wood,” continued the Pigeon, raising its voice to a shriek, “and just as I was thinking I should be free of them at last, they must needs come wriggling down from the sky! Ugh, Serpent!”

“But I’m not a serpent, I tell you!” said Alex. “I’m a—I’m a—”

“Well! What are you?” said the Pigeon. “I can see you’re trying to invent something!”

“I—I’m a little girl,” said Alex, rather doubtfully, as they remembered the number of changes they had gone through that day.

“A likely story indeed!” said the Pigeon in a tone of the deepest contempt. “I’ve seen a good many little girls in my time, but never one with such a neck as that! No, no! You’re a serpent; and there’s no use denying it. I suppose you’ll be telling me next that you never tasted an egg!”

“I have tasted eggs, certainly,” said Alex, who was a very truthful child; “but little girls eat eggs quite as much as serpents do, you know.”

“I don’t believe it,” said the Pigeon; “but if they do, why then they’re a kind of serpent, that’s all I can say.”

This was such a new idea to Alex, that they were quite silent for a minute or two, which gave the Pigeon the opportunity of adding, “You’re looking for eggs, I know that well enough; and what does it matter to me whether you’re a little girl or a serpent?”

“It matters a good deal to me,” said Alex hastily; “but I’m not looking for eggs, as it happens; and if I was, I shouldn’t want yours: I don’t like them raw.”

“Well, be off, then!” said the Pigeon in a sulky tone, as it settled down again into its nest. Alex crouched down among the trees as well as they could, for their neck kept getting entangled among the branches, and every now and then they had to stop and untwist it. After a while they remembered that they still held the pieces of mushroom in their hands, and they set to work very carefully, nibbling first at one and then at the other, and growing sometimes taller and sometimes shorter, until they had succeeded in bringing themselves down to their usual height.

It was so long since they had been anything near the right size, that it felt quite strange at first; but they got used to it in a few minutes, and began talking to themselves, as usual. “Come, there’s half my plan done now! How puzzling all these changes are! I’m never sure what I’m going to be, from one minute to another! However, I’ve got back to my right size: the next thing is, to get into that beautiful garden—how is that to be done, I wonder?” As they said this, they came suddenly upon an open place, with a little house in it about four feet high. “Whoever lives there,” thought Alex, “it’ll never do to come upon them this size: why, I should frighten them out of their wits!” So they began nibbling at the righthand bit again, and did not venture to go near the house till they had brought themselves down to nine inches high.